swgas.com 2019-06-15

# Southwest Gas: Privacy Policy

**Southwest Gas Corporation Online Services Privacy Policy**

Southwest Gas Corporation (also referred to as "we", "us", “our”, “Southwest Gas”, or "the Company") takes individuals' privacy seriously and is committed to preventing unauthorized use of, or access to, personally identifiable information. Southwest Gas protects personally identifiable information through processes and procedures intended to detect, prevent and mitigate the unauthorized use or disclosure of any identifying information. This Online Services Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains how we collect, share, use, and protect information collected when you visit or use Southwest Gas’ website, mobile application, Southwest Gas-branded social media, and/or text message alert service (collectively, our “Online Services”). Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy. By using Southwest Gas’ Online Services, you agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy.

**What Our Privacy Policy Covers**

This Privacy Policy covers the Company's treatment of personally identifiable information that may be collected when you are using, visiting, or have signed up for our Online Services.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Southwest Gas does not own or control or to people that Southwest Gas does not employ or manage.

**Links to Third-Party Sites**

While using our Online Services, you may encounter hypertext links which redirect you to third-party websites that are owned, maintained, or operated by parties other than Southwest Gas. These third-party websites are not under the control of Southwest Gas, and Southwest Gas is not responsible for the contents, links or any changes or updates to these websites. Further, the inclusion of any hypertext links in any of Southwest Gas’ Online Services does not imply endorsement by Southwest Gas of the related third-party website, the website's contents, or any association or affiliation with its operators. These third-party websites may send cookies, log your IP address, and otherwise collect data or solicit personal information from you. Southwest Gas is not responsible for data collected by these third-party websites or any related unauthorized access to your data or use of services as a result of browsing these sites, even if such use was not authorized by you. Southwest Gas does not control and is not responsible for how these websites handle or use your personally identifiable information.

**Information Collection**

You may be asked by the Company to submit personal information such as company account number, name or business entity, email address, birth date, address, zip code, phone number, social security number or tax identification number, driver’s license/identification card information or passport information, when requesting our Online Services. Additionally, we may request third-party information including the name of landlord/property manager or contact information of a caretaker or other representative when applicable. You may also be asked to submit additional personal or financial information, including household annual income, number of members of household, to use certain specific services offered by the Company.

In addition to the aforementioned personal information that may be collected, Southwest Gas may track information such as monthly payment history and preferred payment method which may include account numbers, routing numbers, and return item code (if applicable).

**Information Collected Automatically**

Like many companies, Southwest Gas automatically collects certain anonymous information (e.g. date and time site visited, pages visited, links clicked to route to website, Internet Service Provider used, and Internet Protocol address from which our website was accessed) while customers use our Online Services. We currently use various analytics platforms to perform web measurement and analytics. The information collected may be used for things such as compiling statistics about our Online Services and measuring Online Service activity so that we may update our Online Services to better meet users' needs and interests.

**Security**

In areas of our Online Services where personal information is acquired, the Company uses industry-standard security technology - Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) - to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal and financial information. Your browser must be capable of supporting SSL.

**Cookies**

Cookies are small text files placed on your computer's hard drive by web page servers. When you visit the website or mobile application, Southwest Gas Corporation may utilize "session" cookies, which allow us to verify when you travel from page to page within our online service applications.

Additionally, Southwest Gas uses retargeting tools to better understand customer preferences and to determine the effectiveness of our outreach campaigns. Retargeting is a cookie-based technology that uses Javascript code to “follow” visitors when they leave our website. We use retargeting to operate energy education, public safety and informational campaigns in partnership with third-party vendors. As part of our campaigns, we place pixel tags on individual web pages within our Site to track interest in certain types of web content. These tags are used to obtain information about the computer being used to view Web pages, including the IP address, the user’s operating system, and browser type. Pixel tags provide Southwest Gas and our vendors with information about topics and activities of interest to Site visitors, and the digital advertisements or articles that referred visitors to our Site. Retargeting enables our third-party advertising partners to show you ads about our programs and activities, based on your interests, on other websites.

**Data on website and mobile application usage that we collect using cookies or retargeting is not tied to your personally identifiable information and is only used in aggregate form.**

**Information Use**

**a.** The personal information that you provide us enables you to access various customer services offered through our Online Services. We may use this information to contact you regarding customer services, including but not limited to, responding to an inquiry or a request for services that you send to the Company, sending notifications via email regarding construction and maintenance updates, activities pertaining to our programs or services, providing surveys to help improve our customer service, notifying customers of special events, sharing energy and safety education information, and providing offers related to our products and services that may be of interest to you. If you choose to communicate with the Company by Email, then Email from the Company to you will be considered to be sent with your consent and will be accessible to anyone who has access to your Email.

**b.** In order to provide you with services offered through our Online Services, or to complete transactions or requests initiated by you using our Online Services, we may transfer you to websites operated by third parties that help us provide services to you. In such cases, we will have agreements with those parties under which they will agree to maintain confidentiality of your personally identifiable information and to use it only for the purpose of helping us serve you.

**c.** The Company will not collect or sell your personal information for commercial purposes with third parties or provide your personal information to third parties for the purpose of telemarketing, Email or direct mail solicitation.

**d.** Other than as set forth herein, the Company will not disclose your personal information to third parties without your written consent (which consent may be obtained electronically, such as by Email) unless we reasonably believe that the disclosure is essential to the conduct of the Company's business, including but not limited to:

• Compliance with the law, legal process, or our regulators  
• Collection of unpaid bills  
• Enabling the Company's employees or consultants to provide service to you and to otherwise perform their duties  
• Resolving customer disputes or inquiries  
• Obtaining and providing credit reporting information

**e.** The Company may use customer data such as demographics, premises data, payment history, channel preferences/interactions, and participation in programs and offers, to assist customers in managing their gas service.

**Traffic Data**

In order to improve the usefulness of our Online Services, we automatically collect and maintain statistical information from data logs that concern network traffic flow and volume ("Traffic Data"). This Traffic Data consists of:

• Name of the domain, or URL, from which the visitor accesses the Internet;  
• Internet Protocol ("IP") address;  
• Type of web browser used; and  
• Date and time the website was visited.

Traffic Data does not identify individual visitors. It is used to highlight what our visitors find interesting, to improve the website's design specification, to identify performance issues, and for other internal purposes.

**Location Based Information**

Certain Southwest Gas Online Services provide location services that enable a customer’s location to be determined. If you use a location-based service, we will collect location information about your longitude and latitude and may save your device's coordinates to offer certain features to you.

Location-based services can be disabled through Southwest Gas’ Online Service or the privacy settings on your mobile device.

**California Do Not Track Disclosure**

Under California law, operators of online services are required to disclose how they respond to "do not track" signals or other similar mechanisms that provide consumers the ability to exercise choice regarding the collection of personal information of a consumer over time and across third party online services, to the extent the operator engages in that collection. Like many websites, our Site is not designed to respond to “Do Not Track” signals received from browsers. This law also requires operators of online services to disclose whether third parties may collect personal information about their users' online activities over time and across different online services when the users use the operator's service. We do not knowingly permit third parties to collect personal information about an individual customer’s online activities over time and across different online services when using our Online Services.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

We may from time to time, and without notice, amend, change or modify this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our services and our policies relating to customer information by posting a revised policy. Any revised policy shall be effective immediately on posting. Please check this policy frequently to review our latest changes and our current policy.

**Questions or Suggestions**

If you have questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, contact the Southwest Gas Corporation webmaster at [ webmaster@swgas.com __](mailto:webmaster@swgas.com "webmaster@swgas.com") .

_Last updated December  2018_
